thesolving.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy Policy | The Solving

**Nanosystems S.r.l.** – head / registered office: Via del Commercio 76/A, 63100 Ascoli Piceno (AP) Italy – is committed in protecting your privacy and developing technologies to give you the most secure navigation. Nanosystems S.r.l. is the data owner and controller.

This privacy statement explains data collection and use practices of Nanosystems S.r.l. through the website [**https://thesolving.com**](https://thesolving.com/) (the “Site”) (in this privacy policy, Nanosystems S.r.l. and the Site shall collectively be referred to as “We” or “Nanosystems S.r.l.”).

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

By providing personal information to Nanosystems Srl, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this privacy statement.

READ CAREFULLY THE FOLLOWING TERMS BEFORE USING THIS WEBSITE: THE USAGE, THE REGISTRATION AND THE NAVIGATION THROUGH THIS WEBSITE IMPLY THE ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THESE TERMS, DON’T USE THIS WEBSITE AND DON’T REGISTRATE.

**Types of data collected**  
Nanosystems S.r.l. collects usage data, email address, username, name, last name or company name, VAT ID or fiscal code, phone number and cookies by itself or through third parties.

These personal data may be provided voluntarily by the users or collected during the usage of this website.

This website uses cookies to provide services and improve the user experience, except where stated otherwise. By not providing your personal data, you may not be able to use our services.

The user is responsible for any personal data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the data to the owner.

**Modes of processing data**  
Nanosystems S.r.l. is committed in collecting and processing your data complying with the law.  
The data are processed with the aid of information technologies in Nanosystems Srl headquarters or wherever the parties involved with the processing are located.

The personal data are kept for the time necessary to provide the requested service or stated by the purposes outlined in this agreement. The user can always request the end of the collection and the deletion of his personal data.

Nanosystems S.r.l. is committed in protecting your personal data from unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction. The data are stored in password-protected server with limited access.

For further information about our privacy policy or for support requests about your personal data, you can contact us at the email address **privacy@nanosystems.it**   or at the following address:

Nanosystems S.r.l.  
Via del Commercio, 76/A  
63100 Ascoli Piceno (AP) – Italy  
Tel. +39 0736 618085

**The use of the collected data**  
The data are collected by Nanosystems to provide its services, for the following purposes: analytics, communications via email, comments of the content published on this website and display of content from third party platforms.

The types of data collected for every purpose is specified below in this document.

The personal data will be shared or used complying with the purpose of the collection, except where otherwise consented or when requested by the law.

The email addresses collected as part of the registration procedure aren’t shared with the public, except where otherwise stated in this privacy policy. The email addresses are mainly used to identify the users and to communicate with them, or as specified below.

**Details about the data collection**  
The personal data are collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

**Analytics**  
The services included in this area allow the data owner and controller to analyze the user behaviour during the navigation. 

Nanosystems S.r.l. uses a first party system to analyze data and generate report about the usage of this website.  
Nanosystems collects usage data and cookies.  
The data are collected in Italy.

We also use Google Analytics, provided by Google Inc. (“Google”), to analyze data and generate report about the usage of this website.  
Google may use the data collected to profile the user and provide customized advertisement through its network.  
Google Analytics collects usage data and cookies.  
The data are collected in the USA – [**Privacy Policy**](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [**Opt Out**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

**Communications via email**  
On the [**https://thesolving.com**](https://thesolving.com/) are present several contact forms to allow the users to ask for information or support.  
The user, completing the contact forms, is consenting Nanosystems to send email messages for the specified purposes.  
The data collected are name, last name or company name and email address.  
The data are collected in Italy.

**Comments of the content published on this website**  
This website allows the user to comment the content published with a first party and a third party service. Using the available commenting services, the user is consenting Nanosystems to publish the comments.

The first party service collects name, last name or company name, email address, cookie, usage data and username.  
The data are collected in Italy.

The third party service is provided by Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”). The service allow the user to publish content on both this website and Facebook, if the user chooses to do so. Facebook may use the data collected to profile the user and provide customized advertisement through its network.  
The data collected are cookies and usage data.  
The data are collected in the USA – [**Privacy Policy**](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)

**Display of content from third party platforms**  
The services included in this area allow this website to display content from external platforms. When this external content is showed on a page of this website, even if the user doesn’t interact with it, the provider may collect personal data. Nanosystems S.r.l. adopt two services to display content from external platforms.

The YouTube widget allows to display videos from the YouTube social platform provided By Google Inc. (“Google”) and to integrate them into the website.  
Google may use the data collected to profile the user and provide customized advertisement through its network.  
Google Analytics collects usage data and cookies.  
The data are collected in the USA – [**Privacy Policy**](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

Google Fonts is a service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”) to integrate typefaces inside the pages of this website.  
Google may use the data collected to profile the user and provide customized advertisement through its network.  
Google Analytics collects usage data and cookies.  
The data are collected in the USA – [**Privacy Policy**](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

**Cookie policy**  
This website uses first party and third party coookies to provide a better user experience and for analytics purposes. Nanosystems doesn’t profile the users and adopts only technical cookies, to provide the services in the best possible way.

**What are cookies?**  
Cookies are information stored in your browser whenever you visit a website or access a social network with your PC, smartphone or tablet.  
Each cookie contains several data like the name of the server, a numerical ID and so on.  
Cookies may be stored in your system for the duration of a single session (until you close the browser) or for longer periods of time and may contain a unique identifier.

**What they do?**  
Some cookies are used to allow authentication, monitor sessions and store specific information about the users accessing a website.  
These cookies, named technical cookies, can improve speed and reactivity of a website or, for example, save your preferences about the language.  
A specific kind of cookies, called analytics, are used by the data owner to collect information about the number of users of a website and their behavior. These data are included in report and other statistical tools.  
Another kind of cookies are used to monitor and profile the users. They study their behavior across different websites to provide customized advertisement (Behavioural Advertising). They’re named profiling cookies.

**How can I manage cookies from my browser?**  
_Block third party cookies_  
Third party cookies aren’t often necessary to use a website, so you can configure your browser to refuse them from the options panel.  
_Enable Do Not Track_  
Do Not Track is a feature present in many last generation browsers. Websites supporting this feature, if enabled, should automatically suspend any data collection. Not all websites support Do Not Track.  
_Enable “Incognito mode”_  
With this feature enabled, the browser will delete cookies and history every time you close it. The websites will not remember your account login or your preferences. The data collected during the navigation will still be available to the managers of the websites.  
_Directly delete the cookies_  
Every browser allows the user to delete the stored cookies. New cookies will be stored at every access so it’s important to delete them periodically.

**What technical cookies are used by this website?**  
This website uses the following technical cookies: 

wordpress_**  
wordpress_logged_in_**  
wordpress_test_cookie  
wp-settings-**  
wp-settings-time-**  
privacy_policy  
_pk_id.** (analytics, first party)  
_pk_ref.** (analytics, first party)  
_pk_ses.** (analytics, first party)

These cookies are used for analytics purposes, to save the user session and for other technical reasons. Their purpose is to provide the best user experience during the navigation.

**What third party cookies are used by this website?**  
This website uses the following third party cookies:

__utma (Google Analytics)  
__utma (Google Analytics)  
__utmc (Google Analytics)  
__utmc (Google Analytics)  
__utmz (Google Analytics)  
__utmz (Google Analytics)  
_ga (Google Analytics)  
_gat_site (Google Analytics)  
_gat_store (Google Analytics)

act (Facebook Comments)  
csm (Facebook Comments)  
datr (Facebook Comments)  
fr (Facebook Comments)  
p (Facebook Comments)  
wd (Facebook Comments)  
c_user (Facebook Comments)  
lu (Facebook Comments)  
presence (Facebook Comments)  
s (Facebook Comments)  
xs (Facebook Comments)

ACTIVITY (YouTube)  
APISID (YouTube)  
GEUP (YouTube)  
HSID (YouTube)  
LOGIN_INFO (YouTube)  
PREF (YouTube)  
SAPISID (YouTube)  
SID (YouTube)  
SSID (YouTube)  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE (YouTube)  
YSC (YouTube)  
__utma (YouTube)  
__utmc (YouTube)  
__utmz (YouTube)  
_ga (YouTube)  
dkv (YouTube)  
**.resume (YouTube)

Nanosystems S.r.l. uses Google Analytics, provided by Google Inc. (“Google”), for analytics purposes, the YouTube widget provided by Google Inc. (“Google”) for displaying content from the YouTube platform and Facebook Comments provided by Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”) to allow the users to publish content directly on this website and, if they choose so, on Facebook.

All these third party services use cookies. The cookies may be used to profile the users in order to provide customized advertisement. The user may accept or deny the usage of these cookies, not strictly necessary to provide the services offered in this website. These cookies won’t be used before the acceptance of the user.

The privacy policy for the third party cookies are available here:  

**How can I accept or deny the usage of non-technical cookies?**  
You can accept or deny the usage of non-technical cookies and third party cookies used by this website. At your first access, and in every other access until a preference will be given, this website will ask you the acceptance of the usage of third party cookies. The request will be displayed in a banner on the top of the website.

By clicking “Ok”, by clicking any other link of this website or scrolling down, you’re consenting the usage of third party cookies.

You preference will expire in 12 months.

You can modify your preference or disable third party cookies using this selector:

Allow third party cookies  
Disable third party cookies

**Changes to this privacy policy**  
Nanosystems S.r.l. reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to the users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often. If a user objects to any of the changes to the policy, the user must cease using this website and can request that Nanosystems S.r.l. removes the personal data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all personal data the data controller has about users.
